<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Decima2</title>
    <link>https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Decima2</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 16:46:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Should We Be Worried About AI?</title>
      <link>https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/worryaboutai/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 May 2024 16:46:47 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/worryaboutai/</guid>
      
      <description>The Wonders of AI As AI becomes increasingly complex it can be used to improve the lives of humans. This includes automating decision making processes such as identifying cancerous cells from radiography images to autonomous tractors, to deomocratizing education in remote areas.
AI and Bias However, just as humans can be flawed in their decision making, AI has also been known to get it wrong. As AI requires a large number of real world examples to learn from it is vulnerable to learn harmful societal biases inherent in this data.</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is AI?</title>
      <link>https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/whatisai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:48:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://tortysivill.github.io/decima2.github.io/posts/whatisai/</guid>
      
      <description>Defining AI Artificial Intelligence (AI) refers to the ability of a machine to recreate human behaviour. Machine Learning (which describes algorithms like neaural networks) is a subset of AI.
Machines or Brains? Machine Learning replicates the human ability to learn from experience. A Neural Network algorithm constructs a network of nodes whose connections act like the nuerons in our brain.
When we ask our algorithm to perfom a task, distinguish between images of cats and dogs for example, we feed a large number of examples into the network which uses different layers of nodes to learn the patterns and rules which help to differentiate the images.</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
